Kaia Bergmann-Dean

301-704-4446 | kbergmanndean@gmail.com

Github: kbergmanndean | https://www.linkedin.com/in/kaiabergmann-dean/ | kb-d.herokuapp.com

QUALIFICATION SUMMARY

Full-stack software engineer with experience in Javascript and Ruby on Rails, as well as a wide ranging background in research, environmental conservation, and food service. Through my diverse professional experiences I developed skills in customer service, teamwork, and logical problem solving which bolster my capabilities as a web developer. I have an educational background in art history, and I appreciate and value design as an integral part of web development.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, Javascript, React, HTML, CSS, Git, ActiveRecord

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Museum - https://github.com/kbergmanndean/art_frontend, https://github.com/kbergmanndean/art_project_backend | https://github.com/kbergmanndean/ar

An interactive museum of visual art by women artists

- Utilized Ruby on Rails to write API functionality for back-end
- Used Active Record and Postgresql to design database schema and code database logic
- Used React to create front-end with multiple routes
- Worked with Sass and CSS styling to implement design for client-side interface

MedReady - https://github.com/kbergmanndean/medready | https://youtu.be/yDaJDPpVqiw | medready.herokuapp.com | https://youtu.be/yDaJDPpVqiw | medready.herokuapp.com | https://youtu.be/yDaJDPpVqiw | medready.herokuapp.com | https://youtu.be/yDaJDPpVqiw | medready.herokuapp.com | https://woutu.herokuapp.com | <a href="med

- Accessed an external API using Ruby on Rails to provide seed data
- Built a React front-end with multiple routes
- Used Authentication and Authorization to create individualized login functionality
- Hand drew logo and illustrations for site design

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

James and Hoffman, PC Washington, DC Contract Researcher 08/2020 - 05/2021

- Conducted in-depth research in support of current and projected litigations.
- Assisted attorneys in reviewing and summarizing interview material.

Learned to use HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Ruby, Rails, ActiveRecord

- Compiled and organized research material into spreadsheets and summaries for pleadings.
- Coordinated with other research team members to compile and organize data.

American Conservation Experience

Flagstaff, AZ, Asheville, NC 09/2019 - 03/2020, 9/2020-11/2020

Corps Member

- Assisted the Park Service and Forest Service in Environmental Conservation projects on Nationally protected land.
- Collaborated and camped with other Corps members from our team during projects.
- Trained on and used a variety of manual and power tools to complete projects in maintenance, construction, and restoration.

Pizzeria Paradiso Hyattsville, MD
Server. Trainer 06/2017-08/2019

- Used customer service skills, time management and task management to ensure client satisfaction in a demanding fast paced environment.
- Trained new servers in a team service environment to ensure smooth restaurant operations.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Washington, DC Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program 05/ 2021 - 08/2021

Oberlin CollegeOberlin, OHBachelor's Degree, Art History05/2017

John Frederick Oberlin Scholar